<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-25T18:56:09-05:00</updated><id>https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Lazy Drupalist</title><subtitle>Armchair adventures in Drupal.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Drupal Way Part 8.3.x</title><link href="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/the-drupal-way-part-8-3-x/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Drupal Way Part 8.3.x" /><published>2017-04-17T04:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-17T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/the-drupal-way-part-8-3-x</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/the-drupal-way-part-8-3-x/"><![CDATA[<p>Holey moley what happened?  I was just sitting here, minding my own business, spelunking through a Drupal 7 render array, and when I looked up a techtonic shift had taken place.  One minute “there was a module for that”. You could tweak that module by digging in and twisting a hook to do what you need.  Then Drupal 8 dropped and it all got real.</p>

<p>Once we just had easy-to-remember hook names like:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>hook_field_attach_prepare_translation_alter(&amp;$entity, $context)
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>Now we’re supposed to create endless yaml files and “just write a plugin”.  A what?</p>

<p>I’m no Luddite.  I came to Drupal from the land of objects (and IDE’s and integrated debuggers &amp; profilers) and unlearned my ‘objectivity’, embracing Drupal like a slightly eccentric family member. You might say that for the past 11 or so years I’ve had an ongoing, rather intense, love-hate relationship with Drupal. I love what I’ve been able to accomplish.  From time to time I’ve had issues with various design decisions, but by and large if I stayed close to the current Drupal Way of doing things I’ve always been able to get done what I needed to with a minimum of muss and fuss. It might have been a bit quirky, but Drupal had a way about it.</p>

<p>There has always been <a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blogs/jeff-geerling/the-drupal-way">The Drupal Way</a>.  Over time a person could discover The Way, stay close to it and leverage some incredible technology to create wonderful things.  If you skew toward <a href="http://www.cipsum.com">MBA-Speak</a> you might call it a set of <em>Best Practices</em> for Drupal.  I shy away from that kind of hifalutin talk whenever possible. I just like to get things done and I like to repeatedly get predictable high quality results with minimal stress. Am I lazy? If going out of my way to automate and streamline and create things that work and are extensible so they can handle the unforseen so I can do other fun things makes a person lazy, then yes. Count me in. Until recently if you had the slightest inclination to do the least amount of work possible TDW was a wonderful thing and laziness was rewarded.</p>

<p>And then, Drupal 8. Chaos! Bedlahm! Pandemonium! Don’t get me wrong, it’s some damn fine code, but it’s a huge shift. I think <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">The Way</code> is still out there – evolving, but it’s damn hard to find. I’m having trouble and I have a feeling I’m not alone.  In the past year I’ve been to a DrupalCon, a Drupal Camp and several user group meetings and I keep running into people with basically the same problem:  There ain’t no way!</p>

<p>Peoples… We’re going to find it!  The sooner we do, the sooner we can pop the footrest of our lazyboys back up and do what we do best. <a href="http://thelazydrupalist.com">The Lazy Drupalist</a> will explore my attempts to keep sane and discover best practices for Drupal development while:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Migrating several Drupal 6 sites to Drupal 8</li>
  <li>Managing feature requests for existing Drupal 7 sites</li>
  <li>Creating and deploying sites in D8</li>
</ol>

<p>Is this even possible?  Hell if I know.  Check back in from time to time and see.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Finding sanity and best practices in Drupal land]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22the-drupal-way.jpg%22%7D" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22the-drupal-way.jpg%22%7D" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World</title><link href="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World" /><published>2017-04-16T10:14:55-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-16T10:14:55-04:00</updated><id>https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.thelazydrupalist.com/blog/hello-world/"><![CDATA[<p>Tap. Tap. Tap… Is this thing on ?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Obligatory First Post]]></summary></entry></feed>